COREY

cmyoung0718@gmail.com

cmyoung0718.github.io

502-541-8833

♀ Seattle, WA

in corey-young-0718

Skills

DATA SKILLS

Python (Scikit-Learn, Numpy, Pandas)

Machine Learning

Data Analysis

Natural Language Processing

Data Cleansing and Manipulation

SQL

Data Visualization (Tableau, MatPlotLib, Seaborn)

MongoDB

Hadoop

Hive

BIOLOGY SKILLS

Experimental Design Cell/Tissue Culture PCR

Aseptic Technique

Awards

University of Louisville

School of Aug Interdisciplinary 2014 and Graduate Studies Fellowship Fellowship that paid tuition and stipend during my time in the University of Louisville's Biology PhD program

Summary

Data scientist with a passion for data, research, and science. I strive to utilize my problem solving skills and curiosity to use data to achieve better health care, find solutions for social change, and improve scientific research. I have a background in biological research that helped me to develop a love for research and data. My time at General Assembly added to my knowledge and skills in programming, data analysis, machine learning, big data, and recommendation systems.

Experience

General Assembly

Data Science Immersive

Seattle, WA Oct 2016 to Dec 2016

- Three month intensive course, around 75 hours a week
- Completed projects utilizing machine learning algorithms in Python under strict time constraints
- · Gained the experience and training I needed to take the step from biology to data science
- Strengthened my skills in Python (Scikit-Learn, Pandas, Numpy, MatPlotLib, etc), SQL, MongoDB, Git, command line, machine learning, big data, and data engineering.

The Commonwealth of Kentucky Forensic Biologist 1

Frankfort, KY Dec 2015 to Oct 2016

- Screened evidence for the presence of body fluids using a variety of techniques, including immunodiffusion tests and the Kastle-Meyer test.
- · Prepared chemical reagents used for the screening of evidence
- Received evidence from police agencies around the state according to the Case Acceptance Policy

University of Louisville

Research Assistant

Louisville, KY Aug 2012 to Dec 2015

- Designed protocols and performed experiments accordingly
- Analyzed data to gain insight into how Salmonella is able to cause systemic infections
- Responsible for training and supervising new research assistants
- Helped to develop a new in vitro assay to study how Salmonella causes systemic infections
- Helped secure a federal grant worth over \$500,000

Education

General Assembly
Data Science Immersive 2016

University of Louisville Graduate Work

University of Louisville BA in Biology 2014

Activities

I am also very interested in all things music. I am a mostly self-taught guitarist with a moderate amount of knowledge in music theory.